BEHROOZ FAREED

+923454492492 | Behroozfareed100@gmail.com

CAREER SUMMARY

Experienced professional with 05 years of diverse experience in Finance & Accounts and ERP with reputed organizations in different sectors of services & manufacturing industries. Proficient in project management with the ability to multitask and manage tight deadlines. Team player who enjoys working in a challenging environment with learning opportunities. Able to work in a fast-paced environment with the ability to take independent and prompt decisions.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bio Tech Energy (PVT) Limited

Assistant Manager Accounts October 2021 to present

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

- Assisting Manager Accounts in the preparation of monthly and quarterly accounting reports.
- Ensuring the compliance of financial statements with IAS, IFRS and GAAP.
- Performing reconciliations of general ledger accounts.
- Supervising and providing overall guidance to sub-ordinate accounts' staff.
- Providing regular updates to management regarding company financial position.
- Ensuring that the company maintains compliance with accounting legislation.
- Assisting senior managers in the preparation of monthly and quarterly accounting report.
- Liaison with banks concerning imports & exports related operations.
- · Developing and refining Payroll procedures.

Kickstart Co-Working

Accounts Executive
October 2019 to August 2021

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

- Looking after Cash Disbursement, Expense Recording, Accounts payables and receivables, prepare reconciliation statements of receivables and payables.
- Prepare, examine, and analyze accounting records and incoming documents to assess accuracy, completeness, and conformance to reporting and procedural standards and to avoid adjustments to entries.
- Liaise with banks, auditors, clients, suppliers, and all third parties dealing with the company and preserve relationships with the same.
- Reconciliation of vendor's statement of accounts.
- Enter trade payable invoices & make payments as per due dates.
- Making of month end closing adjustments.
- Provide reports to management to enable them to make better plans and organize business operations.
- Making of customers aging reports and write offs of bad debts.
- Coordinating with project engineers regarding invoicing and other matters of clients.
- Correspondence to Banks, Insurance Companies and other related companies.
- To Ensure the compliance of IFRS, Tax laws and SECP Laws.

Zahid Jamil & Co Chartered Accountants

Audit & Accounts Associate

September 2016 to August 2019

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

I have worked as audit associate at Zahid Jamil & Co Chartered Accountants (A member firm of prime global international) for 3 years. I have been part of leading assurance and advisory client sector including financial services, Manufacturing, Utility, Telecommunication, Real Estate, Textile and Services sector.

During my stay at ZJC & Co, I have gathered appreciable experience in Statuary audit, internal audit and other related advisory services rendered to different public and private limited companies, independently as well as team leader/member.

Outsourced Accountant

Outsourced at SWVL & Kickstart by Zahid Jamil & Co Chartered Accountants

- Regular Accounting & Bookkeeping of all Transactions at client's office premises.
- Day to day tax compliance of income tax and Punjab sales tax laws.
- Preparation of invoices, salary sheets, bank reconciliation and all accounting related vouchers.
- Ensuring the accuracy of financial documents, as well as their compliance with relevant standards, laws and regulations.
- Offering guidance on cost reduction, revenue enhancement and profit maximization.
- Management of Accounts Payables and Accounts Receivables as per company's rules.

External Audit

- Engagement planning, execution and finalization of statutory audit/review of annual/half yearly/quarterly financial statements in accordance with International Standard on Auditing (ISAs), International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRSs).
- Analysis and review of financial and non-financial information.
- Timely preparation of all deliverables including Separate and Consolidated Financial Statements, Management Letters, Audit Reports, and other Deliverables.
- Liaison between client/Engagement and Firm/Partner.
- Consultation on significant matters with various professionals such as lawyers, tax advisors and actuaries as well as evaluating the implication of their opinions from an accounting perspective.

Internal Audit

- Conducting audit in accordance with International Standards for The Professional Practice of Internal Audit.
- System Reviews, Design testing of Process manual, evaluating management procedures and operations to ensure the company is operating as efficiently as possible while remaining within established corporate policies and government regulations.
- Conducting detail testing of various departmental operations within different organizations to assess effectiveness and efficiency in compliance to management instruction, policies and procedures.
- Internal Audit Report Writing and Presentation to Audit Committee.
- Analysis and review of financial and non-financial information.
- Timely preparation of all deliverables including Management Letters, Audit Reports and other Deliverables.
- Liaison between client/Engagement and Firm/Partner.
- Consultation on significant matters with various professionals such as lawyers, tax advisors and actuaries as well as evaluating the implication of their opinions from an accounting perspective.

SKILLS

- Proficient in Oracle, Xero, Quick books and hands on experience of SAP.
- I am proficient in Microsoft Office.
- Experienced in working as team member and in individual capacity.
- Good Communication skills.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

ACCA Member - 2019
Association of Chartered Certified Accountants

Foundation in Accountancy - 2015
Association of Chartered Certified Accountants

CERTIFICATES

- Advance Diploma in Accountancy and Business.
- Diploma in Accounting and Business.
- Foundation Diploma.
- · Certificate of Achievement in Foundation Financial Accounting.

All certificates have been awarded by Association of Chartered Certified Accountants.

OTHER INFO

Date of Birth: April 05, 1997

Nationality: Pakistan

Hobbies & Interests: Books reading, Blogs reading, Farming, Travelling and Playing cricket.